machinio.com 2019-04-17

# Machinio.com Privacy

Last Revised: April 10, 2019

## Notice of Privacy Rights

Machinio, (“Machinio,” “we,” or “us”) welcomes you to www.machinio.com and any and all applications or mobile applications offered by Machinio Corp., 190 S LaSalle #560, Chicago, IL 60603, USA (the “Site”). This Privacy Policy describes how Machinio collects and receives information about you through the Site, Services and Content and through Machinio’s businesses, including offline. The Privacy Policy together with the Terms of Use govern your use of the Site and Machinio’s collection and use of your information.

Machinio participates in the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding certain personal information received by Machinio in the U.S. from European Union member countries. Please find below information for EU member states citizens about Machinio’s data practices regarding personal information it receives from European Union member countries pursuant to the Privacy Shield framework. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program generally, and to view Machinio’s certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

Should the Privacy Policy be revised, Machinio will post the changes on the Site which will be effective immediately upon posting. Any material changes to the terms of the Privacy Policy will apply only to information collected thereafter. You can determine when the Privacy Policy was last revised by referring to the “Last Revised” legend at the top of this page.

If you provide your personal information to Machinio offline, the Privacy Policy applies to Machinio’s collection and use of your information. Machinio also may provide paper copies of the Privacy Policy when it collects information from you offline.

Controller in terms of data protection law is Machinio Corp. 190 S LaSalle #560, Chicago, IL 60603 USA.

The responsible person for data protection can be reached at dataprivacy@machinio.com.

## INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT

## Customer Data:

We collect personal information from you which you provide voluntarily including, without limitation, personal information about you that helps Machinio identify you such as first and last name, email or postal address and other information that is not otherwise publicly available (collectively, “Personal Information”).

We collect this personal information:

  * to enable performance of contract, i.e. connecting potential buyers and sellers through our platform, by forwarding potential buyer data to sellers;
  * to process and respond to your inquiries;
  * to administer Content or Services;
  * to enforce the Terms of Use;
  * for the purposes for which you provided the information.

If you decide to register for e-mail alerts, we store email address and potential keywords:

  * to alert you to new features, terms, Content, Services, or products;
  * to send emails or newsletters, and to provide you with personalized content in the newsletters.

We collect Customer Data on basis of Art. 6 para 1 (b) GDPR ("contractual necessity").

## Traffic Data:

We also collect information automatically about your use of the Site such as your IP address, usage statistics, browsing history, types of computers and/or mobile devices accessing the Site, Content or Services, type of computer operating system you use (e.g., Microsoft Windows or Mac OS), the type of browser you use (e.g., Firefox, Chrome, Internet Explorer), and the domain name of your internet service provider (collectively, “Traffic Data”).

We use Traffic Data for the following purposes:

  * to provide information to third parties that may provide you with personalized content and advertising about their stores, restaurants, products and services.
  * to monitor and analyze information regarding your browsing and viewing preferences.
  * to analyze our users’ demographics and interests.
  * to improve the Site.

## HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION

We collect personal information from you when you use the Site or register an account to access Content or Services provided on the Site or to request to receive emails or newsletters that may be offered on the Site or offline.

Machinio may automatically receive and record non-personal information on our server logs from your browser as well as through other analysis of the Site. We also may collect information using cookies, web beacons or similar technologies, or through third parties using similar technologies.

## A. Cookies

We use “cookies” to customize your experience with the Site, Content and Services and to store your information so you do not have to re-enter them each time you visit the Site or access the Content or Services. Cookies are small computer files that are transferred to your hard drive and contain information such as your username, user preferences, the web pages you’ve visited and the activities you’ve performed while using the Site, Content or Services. You may block or delete cookies from your hard drive; however, by disabling cookies, you may not have access to all of the Services or Content. Our cookies are deleted after 12 months.

Some of our business partners also use cookies to provide us with anonymous, aggregate data and information regarding our users. We do not have access or control over these cookies, and our Privacy Policy does not cover the use of third party cookies.

## B. Web Beacons

We or our third party tracking utility company also use “web beacons” to collect information about your use of our Site, the websites of selected sponsors and advertisers, and our Content and Services. Web beacons are tiny graphic image files embedded in a web page or email that provide a presence on the web page or email and send back to its home server information from the user’s browser. The information collected by web beacons allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using our Site and Services, selected sponsors’ and advertisers’ websites and using our Services and for what purposes.

## WHERE WE PROCESS INFORMATION

Personal information collected by Machinio are be stored and processed in the United States in accordance with the laws of the United States, or in other jurisdiction.

## COMMUNICATIONS WITH YOU

If Machinio contacts you due to your subscription to receive promotional information by email, you can unsubscribe to such communications according to the unsubscribe instructions which are included in each promotional email from Machinio. Alternatively you may sent an email requesting to opt-out of communications to dataprivacy@machinio.com. Please note that such requests may take up to ten (10) days to become effective. You cannot opt out of receiving communications regarding your dealings with Machinio or the Site, Content, Services or technical information about the Site, which is indispensable for the provision of our Services and Content.

## INFORMATION SHARING WITH THIRD PARTIES

We do not sell or share your personal information to any third party (except as set out in this Privacy Policy) without your consent.

Machinio discloses anonymized traffic data: (i) to affiliates, merchants, licensors, partners or sponsors, and other third parties for their own direct marketing purposes, such as to provide information to you about their stores, activities, products, services and other important information; (ii) to third parties to provide analytics for advertising purposes or to confirm or update information provided by you; (iii) to suppliers, vendors and others who help Machinio provide services to you, such as outsourcing one or more of the functions described in this Privacy Policy; (iv) to third parties in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or disposition of all or any portion of Machinio’s business or operations (including without limitation in connection with bankruptcy or any similar proceedings); or (v) as otherwise authorized by you.

In case of a subpoena, court order or official request, we may share your personal information to investigate, prevent or take action regarding suspected illegal activities, fraud or potential threats, or exercise legal rights or defend against claims, when we believe that doing so may protect your safety or the safety of Machinio or others, or as otherwise permitted or required by law.

We also use and share anonymized or aggregate information with third parties. Additionally, we take personal information and anonymize it and share it in a anonymized or aggregated form with advertisers, business partners, and/or third parties in order to analyze Site usage, perform services on our Site or others’ Site, improve our services, improve our user experience, or for similar purposes.

Moreover, we share your personal data with third parties when you make a request for equipment or machinery. The prospective seller will receive your email address after sending your request.

Furthermore, we send out monthly reportings to our customers including a list of company names associated with users which viewed the customers' listings. Before we create the monthly reporting we process the users' personal information and anonymize it to be able to create the above mentioned list.

## CHILDREN

The Site is not directed toward children under 16 years of age nor does Machinio knowingly collect information from children under age 16 on the Site or offline. If you are under 16, you are not permitted to register for emails or newsletters or to otherwise submit any personal information to Machinio. If a child under the age of 16 submits personal information to Machinio's web sites, we delete the information as soon as we discover it was provided by a child under 16 years of age and do not use it for any purpose.

## PROTECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

Machinio uses appropriate technical and organizational measures to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of personal information.

However, no transmission of data over the internet is completely secure. It may be possible for third parties not under the control of Machinio to intercept or access transmissions or private communications unlawfully. Any such transmission of your information is at your own risk. For any transmission of data over the internet we recommend to use means improving data protection such as firewalls, antivirus software and similar technologies.

## UPDATING YOUR INFORMATION

Please update your information by contacting us at dataprivacy@machinio.com or editing your account information to keep your information current. We will use reasonable efforts to process any change you make; provided, however, that requests to delete information are subject to Machinio’s internal reporting, processing and retention policies and all applicable legal obligations.

## NOTICE OF PRIVACY RIGHTS OF CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS

If you are a California resident and have provided personal information to Machinio, you are entitled by law to request certain information regarding any disclosure that may have been made by Machinio to third parties of personal information for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, send a message to dataprivacy@machinio.com.

The message should specify that you seek your “California Customer Choice Privacy Notice.” Please allow thirty (30) days for a response. Machinio is required to respond to only one request per customer each year, and is not required to respond to requests made by means other than through the above e-mail address.

We will not share your personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes if you request that we do not do so. You may make such a request by sending us a message at dataprivacy@machinio.com.

When contacting us, please indicate your name, address, email address, and what personal information you do not want us to share with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Please note that there is no charge for controlling the sharing of your personal information or for processing this request.

## LINKS

You may have the opportunity to follow links on the Site to other sites that may be of interest to you. Machinio endeavors to only link to reputable organizations. Because other sites may not be hosted or controlled by Machinio, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of those sites or the content provided thereon. Therefore, the privacy policies with respect to other site may differ from those applicable to the Site. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of each other site. This Privacy Policy only applies to information collected and maintained by Machinio.

## INFORMATION FOR EU MEMBER STATES CITIZENS ONLY

Machinio complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention processing of personal information transferred from Individual Customers in the European Union member countries. Machinio has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Privacy Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. If there is any conflict between the policy in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

## ACCESS

If you request information as to whether personal data relating to you is being processed or whether you wish to access, correct, update or delete your personal data, you can contact us at any time by contacting us at dataprivacy@machinio.com.

If you are a resident of the European Union, you can also object to the processing of your personal data, ask us to restrict the processing of your personal data or request the transfer of your personal data. You can also exercise these rights by contacting us at dataprivacy@machinio.com.

You have the right at any time to refuse the sending of advertising messages that we send to you. You can unsubscribe at any time via the link provided in the newsletter or by sending us a corresponding message.

You can also revoke your consent at any time if we collect and process your personal data with your consent. The revocation of your consent has no influence on the legality of the processing of your personal data, which we have carried out before the revocation of your consent, nor on the processing of your personal data, which we have carried out on the basis of a legitimate interest and for which no consent is required.

You have the right to complain to a data protection authority about the collection and use of your personal data. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority.

## CHOICE

You have the right to opt out of disclosure of your Personal Data to third parties not identified at the time of collection or subsequently authorized, and the use of your Personal Data for a purpose materially different from the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized. In order for you to access our services, we may require you to provide us with Personal Information. Machinio’s use of any Personal Information will be solely for the purpose for which the information was originally collected.

To exercise any of your rights, please contact us at dataprivacy@machinio.com. Machinio will act upon any such requests in accordance with applicable data protection laws, and may ask you to verify your identity in order to help us respond efficiently to your request.

## ACCOUNTABILITY FOR ONWARDS TRANSFER

Prior to disclosing Personal Information to a third party, Machinio will notify you of such disclosure and allow you the choice of opting out. In those instances where you have consented to the disclosure of your Personal Information to a third party acting as an agent, Machinio agrees to take steps to confirm that any third party to whom Personal Information may be disclosed is subject to legal requirements that provide the same level of privacy protection as is required by the Privacy Shield Principles, agrees in writing to provide an adequate level of privacy protection and will notify Machinio if it makes a determination that it can no longer meet this obligation. Machinio does not share data with non-agent third parties. In cases of onward transfers to third parties of data of EU individuals received pursuant to the EU-US Privacy Shield, Machinio is potentially liable, unless Machinio proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. Machinio may be required to disclose an individual’s personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including meeting a national security or law enforcement request.

## SECURITY

Wherever Machinio stores or processes personal information from the European Union into other jurisdictions, Machinio takes reasonable steps and appropriate measures to protect personal data covered by this Privacy Shield Policy from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alternation, and destruction, taking into account the risks involved in the processing and nature of personal data.

## DATA INTEGRITY AND PURPOSE LIABILITY

Machinio limits the collection of personal data covered by this Privacy Shield Policy to information that is relevant for the purposes of processing. Machinio does not process such personal data in a way that is incompatible with the purposes for which it has been collected or subsequently authorized by the data subject.

Machinio takes reasonable steps to ensure that personal data is reliable for its intended use, accurate, complete, and current. Furthermore, Machinio takes reasonable and appropriate measures to comply with the requirement under the Privacy Shield to retain personal data in identifiable form only for as long as it serves a purpose of processing, which includes Machinio’s obligations to comply with professional standards, Machinio’s business purposes and unless a longer retention period is permitted by law, and it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles for as long as it retains such personal data.

## RECOURSE, ENFORCEMENT & LIABILITY

Machinio commits to periodically review and verify its compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, and to resolve any complaints arising out of failure to comply with the Privacy Shield Principles.

In compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles, Machinio commits to resolve complaints concerning your privacy and our collection of your personal data within 45 days of receiving a complaint. If you have any questions about this Policy or would like to request access to your personal data or if you have complaints regarding this Privacy Policy and our use of your personal data, please contact us as follows:

Machinio Corp.

190 S LaSalle #560

Chicago, IL 60603

USA

Machinio has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles to an independent recourse mechanism, JAMS EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by Machinio, please visit <https://www.jamsadr.com/file-an-eu-us-privacy-shield-or-safe-harbor-claim> for more information and to file a complaint at no cost to you.

In addition, the United States Federal Trade Commission is the statutory body that has jurisdiction to hear any claims against Machinio regarding compliance with the Privacy Shield. Under certain conditions individuals may be able invoke binding arbitration before the Privacy Shield Panel.

## CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY SHIELD POLICY

Machinio reserves the right to amend this Privacy Shield Policy from time to time, consistent with the requirements of the Privacy Shield. Appropriate notice regarding such amendments will be given.
